As I've been teaching PMP Exam preps for a long time and I've taught this all over the U.S. all over
the world and online and noticed a common theme among p.m.-I candidates among PMP candidates and it's
they often have a tendency to over think the questions because there's They want to be so certain to
pass this exam they want to be so certain that they're right that often they look at a question and
they begin to legitimize answers rather than just taking the question at face value.
So you can't read too much into a question you just answer the question.
So don't think too much Don't over think this along that same line.
I've noticed that people who often mail the exam and there have been some folks that don't pass on the
first attempt they tend to be just really dreading the exam and putting it off and putting it off and
they take a long time to prepare.
So I've really come to the conclusion that the longer you take to prepare at some point you have a drop
off.
So I think for most people about four to six weeks is it that you need to have an intense study time
about four to six weeks.
But if you take beyond that I believe there's a risk that your retention and interest really begin to
fade and drop off because you've got life you've got work you've got other things you're interested
in.
And the longer you take to study you're just going to lose touch with things that happen early in the
course and early in your study efforts.
I find that of most people they can compact it to about four to six weeks and that seems like a lot.
But it's really not too bad.
Four to six weeks of intense studying.
And I know you have other commitments and you've got work and so on.
So that may not be realistic for everyone but I would not take a year to study to pass this test.
I would encourage people to try to compact your schedule.
Then don't overthink answers.
But I want you to have confidence that you can do this.
Don't be afraid of this.
I think afraid robs more people of success than failure ever does.
So don't fear this.
This is something you can do.
It's just a test and it's a test that I have confidence you can pass.
So have that confidence.
Don't over think compact your efforts and get it done.
All right keep moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.